Alec Venida

alecvenidadev@gmail.com (714) 349-1338 <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

PROJECTS

YouTut (React, Redux, Node.js, Python, Flask, AWS S3, CSS3, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, Docker, Heroku)

Live Site | Github

A fullstack YouTube clone specializing in online tutorials, where users can stream, upload, and comment on videos.

- Integrated Amazon Web Services (AWS) S3 to allow users to upload and store their own video and image files.
- Implemented the use of the React Player Component to allow the display of video streams via youtube, vimeo, or my own AWS S3 bucket.
- Implemented a shuffling algorithm to mix seeded data with every render of a page for variety and user engagement.
- Implemented a search feature using React manipulation to allow users to topically find videos or other users.
- Designed custom error handling when uploading videos, to ensure that videos were in an acceptable format and size, informing users if their submissions were wrong, and preventing the passing of bad data to the backend.

Instacrumbz (React, Redux, Python, Flask, HTML5, CSS, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, Docker, Heroku)

Live Site | Github

A fullstack Instagram clone where users can upload posts, add photos, add comments, and like their favorite posts or images.

- Worked in a small group using AGILE frameworks to produce a fully functional full-stack application in one weeks' time.
- Oversaw and facilitated the seeding and deployment of the application to heroku via Docker Container.
- Championed use of a Kanban system, increasing organization, timeliness, TDD, accountability, and allowing team members to specialize in portions of the project.
- Integrated and maintained the deletion and updating of comments.
- Maintained the frontend single post component to match that of the target site.
- Communicated effectively with the team to assist with errors, freeing up time and raising morale.

Mic-Lockr (React, Redux, Express, Sequelize, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Heroku)

Live Site | Github

A fullstack Flickr clone where users can share images of their favorite microphones, and leave comments.

- Implemented AWS S3 to allow users to upload their own image files.
- Allowed users to create, update, delete, and read images and comments through fetch calls and state management with Redux.
- Designed back end using RESTful APIs so that users have a streamlined experience to access relevant table information.
- Executed Bootstrap framework integration for transitions, standardization, design, and usability.

SKILLS React, Redux, Javascript (ES6), Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Docker, Heroku, Node.js, AWS S3

EXPERIENCE

LASC Irvine, Adult ESL Teacher Irvine, CA

July 2018-November 2021

- Teaching English to foreign and international students of multiple levels and backgrounds for academic and business purposes.
- Taught classes in preparation for Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL), as well as English for business settings.
- Assessed and placed incoming students from over 20 countries and language backgrounds.
- Lead many to become successful lawyers, dentists, restaurateurs, small business owners, and/or college graduates.

Asco Coburg Sprachenschule, Teacher Coburg, Germany

February 2014 - October 2016

- Developed and executed courses in English as a foreign language to students in company and business settings.
- Assessed and coached individual and group clients to use English in a corporate, professional and/or global environment.
- Listened to company needs and goals, and implemented curriculum, assessment, and follow-up.
- Successfully trained for various departments, from Human Resources, to Engineering, Production, Distribution, and Marketing.

EC San Diego, Lead Teacher San Diego, CA

February 2011 - January 2014

- Developed and delivered English courses in a classroom setting to learners from over 20 countries.
- Wrote, led, and delivered workshops for my peers for continuing professional development.
- Assessed and placed incoming students for groups as large as 100 a week.

EDUCATION

App Academy Full-time Immersive Online Program. February 2022 - October 2022

• 1,000+ hour immersive full stack software engineering program.

University of California, San Diego July 2010.

• BA Creative Writing and Literature.